# LUIS PABLO LORENCEZ SANTILLÁN

5637296955 luislorencezsantillan@gmail.com 

✓

https:/www.linkedin.com/in/pablolorencez in





#### **SUMMARY**

Extensive experience working in administration for SMEs, of which 3 years have involved working with an ERP system, performing support and training tasks besides procurement processes and supply management.

In this sense, I have one year of preparation in SAP MM module (Udemy course and academic preparation in EHP 6.0 manuals) and practices in SAP system s4hana 2020. I'm familiar with ITIL Methodology, ServiceNow for tickets handling and SLAs.

I've developed some skills focused on Political Science, specifically on education and researching. With a couple years as an associate professor in the National University of México and as a part of a few projects from which a couple of publications with the theme of socio-territorial vulnerability derive.



#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Administration | Farmacia San Pedro.

NOVEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

- Purchasing and inventory management.
- Suppliers mangement.
- Accounts, payments and financial reports.
- Operational regulations and guidelines for best practice management.
- Customer service.
- Staff management.

## Associate Professor | Facultad de Ciencias Políticas y Sociales, UNAM

FEBRERO 2019 – JULIO 2021

#### Courses taught:

- Public space and citizenship; Mexico in the context of a global society Karla Valverde, Ph.D.
- World History I; World History II Luis Alberto de la Garza, Ph.D.

#### Tasks:

- Planning lessons.
- Follow up of attendance, homework and evaluations.
- · Didactic planning.

#### Intern – Research Assistant | Facultad de Ciencias Políticas y Sociales, UNAM.

DECEMBER 2018 - NOVEMBER 2020

Project PAPIIT: IG300118 "Vulnerabilidad socio-territorial y proceso metropolitano en la región centro de México". UNAM. Head researcher: Karla Valverde, Ph.D.

- Research and write papers, reports, and summarized information.
- Organization of seminars and colloquiums.
- Activities management with relevant agents for urban improvement.
- Support the project website on the WordPress platform.

#### Administration | fleet of vehicles for transport network companies.

DECEMBER 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2019

- Operational procedures management.
- Staff management.
- Profit and Loss Statements.
- Management of the expenses of the units



#### EDUCATION

Political Sciences and Public Administration | Faculty of Social and Political Sciences, National Autonomous University of Mexico.

#### **COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS**

English for Business and Entrepreneurship | University of Pennsylvania.

Google Project Management Professional Certificate | Google – Coursera.

SAP MM Training | Udemy.

OPEN Data Science | BEDU.









English for Business.pdf

Cert\_gestión de proyectos.pdf

OPEN Ciencia de Datos.pdf

Sap MM.pdf

#### **LANGUAJES**

English (fluent)
Spanish (native)



Inglés\_ENALLT.pdf



#### **SKILLS**

- SAP MM
- ServiceNow (ITIL methodology)

- Microsoft Office
- Wordpress
- Asana and Trello (Agile methodology and Scrum framework)



### **PAPERS**

- Lorencez, L. (2021). La ciudad neoliberal. Desigualdad y exclusión social en la periferia de la Ciudad de México: el caso de Cuautitlán Izcalli. En Karla Valverde Viesca y Dianell Pacheco Gordillo (Coordinadoras), Ciudades cohesionadas. Co-crear agendas urbanas incluyentes. México: UNAM. In press.
- Lorencez, L.; Mondragón, G.; Valverde, K. (2021). El presupuesto participativo en el Pedregal de Santo Domingo. Una mirada desde la metodología de Co-Creación. En Maximiliano García Guzmán (Coordinador), Tendencias del análisis de políticas públicas en México. Estudios de caso en México. México: UNAM. In press.